[Sportractive](http://sportractive.com/index.php) Toggle navigation

1\. Privacy policy for the website
==================================

Are you interested in what happens to your data? Excellent! Privacy is also important to us. On this page we explain what personal data we collect and process on our website and why.

For our website we use proven technologies with low exposure to attack. We do not use social plugins, cookies, or Google Analytics. You can use our website without having to provide any personal data.

Privacy
-------

Privacy is about protecting your fundamental rights. As the owner of this website ([Imprint](http://sportractive.com/index.php?link=imprint)) we are responsible for that. As a small organisation we are not required to appoint a data protection officer, but we do obtain advice from a [data protection professional](https://datenschutz-individuell.de/).

The affected person is you, the user of the website. Personal data is information that relates to you as an individual. Processing this data means any handling such as collection, processing, use and deletion.

Logging
-------

Our web server is operated by a specialized [company](http://df.eu/) and logs the following data for each call:

* Date and time, called address (URL) and your IP address
* Information that your browser sends (eg browser type and version, operating system, previously loaded URL),

The data we collect helps us to operate and optimize the website. We do not use it to draw conclusions about you. We note that, in some circumstances, we may be required by law to provide the information we collect to authorities. Logs older than seven days will be anonymized. The anonymized data is statistically evaluated and not deleted.

Your rights
-----------

We must not collect personal data from you without your knowledge. The above describes the information that we collect. We do not collect any other information when you visit the website.

You have the right to ask us what we know about you and what we do with your data.

You also have the right to require us to correct or delete your personal data, or restrict its processing and movement (such as export of your personal data). However, you should note that the only personal data we collect is your IP addresses. We have no way of associating that address with you as an individual.

If you have an issue with our data protection practices please contact us in the first instance by [Email](mailto:privacy@sportractive.com?subject=Privacy). If you are dissatisfied with our response you can submit a complaint to the BayLDA which is the relevant authority: [https://www.lda.bayern.de/en/complaint.html](https://www.lda.bayern.de/en/complaint.html).

If you have any questions please contact us: [Email](mailto:privacy@sportractive.com?subject=Privacy)!

2\. Privacy policy for the Sportractive app
===========================================

The Sportractive app uses the following personal data:

* Birthday: For the calculation of the heart rate zone and the body measure
* Weight: To calculate the energy consumption of a workout and the body measure
* Gender: To calculate the energy consumption of a workout and the body measure
* Size: To calculate the energy consumption of a workout and the body measure

The Sportractive app can be used without the above mentioned data. But the functionality of energy and heart rate zone calculation is not given then.

These personal data will remain exclusively on the phone and are not transmitted through the Sportractive App. By uninstalling the Sportractive App these data will also be deleted.

The Sportractive app uses the current GPS position consisting of longitude and latitude to load the map from Google.com and the local weather data from Sportractive.com. Together with the weather data, error counters are transmitted. These contain no personal data and are used for debugging. The GPS position, rounded to degrees, is used to load the digital elevation model from Sportractive.com. The loading of the digital elevation model can be deactivated. If the Sportractive App crashes, a bug report is sent to Sportractive.com. This bug report does not contain any personal information and ist used for debugging only.

No registration or internet community membership is needed to use the Sportractive App.

The Sportractive app offers sharing, sync, upload and export functions. With these a user can share data, entered or collected by the use of the app, with other apps or internet services.

Sportractive supports data exchange via Health Connect from version 5.2 and Android 9. The user can grant the following health-related permissions:

* Read & Write Body Measurement data: Weight, Body Fat
* Write Workout data: Exercise, Exercise Route, Heart Rate, Speed, Distance, Elevation Gained, Total Calories Burned

This data is collected solely for the purpose of improving the user experience and providing functions related to health and fitness. This data is processed locally on the user's device and is not passed on to third parties. The user has the option to grant or deny these permissions within the app settings.

Sportractive does not transmit user data to a third party. Security procedures are in place to protect the confidentiality of your information. Sportractive uses encryption methods to protect your data.

The Sportractive app Data Sync can store workouts, body measurements and other data on Google Drive for Apps and additionally synchronize between a user's devices. The data is stored encrypted in a protected directory on Google Drive for Apps. Other apps do not have access to it and the Sportractive app does not have access to other data in Google Drive.

To provide Sportractive app Data Sync, we may require you to provide us, either directly or indirectly, with certain personally identifiable information, including but not limited to user name, email, and Oauth2 credentials. The information that we request will be retained by us only for technical reasons. We do not give this personal information to others. And we do not use it for marketing or advertising. The Sportractive app Data Sync uses the Google App drive service. The privacy policy can be found here: [Google Sign-in and Google Drive Services](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/)

The Sportractive app Data Sync uses Google's Firebase Cloud Messaging (FCM) technology. For this purpose, the app generates a device-related and a user-related identifier and stores them at Sportractive. The identifier is used exclusively for synchronization. FCM is only used to start the synchronization and not to transfer data. FCM is set to be as data-saving as possible.

The Sportractive app is available in different variants. Each variant has a start icon in a different color. Only the variant with the dark blue icon uses AdMob by Google to display ads. With this variant, AdMob allows you to block certain ads by following Google's instructions: https://support.google.com/ads/answer/2662922 . For more information about how Google handles the information it collects, please visit: http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/ or visit Google's privacy policy: http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/ . Here you will find a link that allows you to turn personalized advertising on and off.

Data entered or collected by use of the Sportractive app will be stored in the hidden app folder on your mobile device. Unless the security mechanisms of the mobile device have been bypassed, the data can only be read by the app itself.

We recommend installing firmware updates from the manufacturer immediately, set up a secure device lock and enable device encryption.

Each user has the right to ask if and what kind of information is stored about him/her. Users also have the right to correct, restrict the processing and deletion of the data as well as data portability. Requests can be sent to [privacy@sportractive.com](mailto:privacy@sportractive.com).

If you feel the need to make a complaint about Sportractive’s data protection practices, the relevant authority is the [BayLDA](https://www.lda.bayern.de/de/beschwerde.html) .

[Imprint](http://sportractive.com/index.php?link=imprint&lang=en) | [Privacy Policy](http://sportractive.com/index.php?link=privacypolicy&lang=en) | [de](http://sportractive.com/index.php?link=start&lang=de) | [en](http://sportractive.com/index.php?link=start&lang=en) | [pt](http://sportractive.com/index.php?link=start&lang=pt) | [fr](http://sportractive.com/index.php?link=start&lang=fr) | Copyright 2019 Sportractive.
